Good evening everyone listening to JWave Wow Music.
Each month, one creator navigates the show as a monthly presenter, introducing a piece of music that he or she thinks is amazing, and then we have a late night music discussion with the creator of the amazing music!
May's monthly presenter is History's Mr. Ikeda.
I've been a guest before, so I've already taken the liberty of doing so.
Yes, I hope I can speak freely and openly.
Today, I would like to welcome Mr. Taihisa Okazaki as our guest for a late-night music discussion.
Actually, we seem to be very close to each other, but this is the first time we've had a proper talk.
So I'm really looking forward to it.
I'm not sure if we'll have enough time for one hour, but I'd like to talk about a lot of things.
I'm not sure if an hour will be enough, but I'd like to talk about many things.
I'm not sure if I'll have enough time for one hour.
Mm-hmm.
Mnh-mnh.
I don't know if one hour is enough.
mmm
WOW MUSIC
J-WAVE WOW MUSIC
Today we welcome Mr. Okazaki Taiko!
Pleased to meet you.
It's been a while.
We haven't talked properly, have we?
We've never really talked in a setting like this.
I've always wanted to come for dinner.
Please take me with you.
Will you take me?
I'll take you, but just in case, sir.
Let's start with your musical roots.
How old are you this year?
Thirty-three this year.
Thirty-three?
Up to 1989.
Eighty-nine.
I was 15 or 6.
Yang Yang, I see. Do you remember what happened in '89?
Higuchi: In '89, I took the high school entrance exam.
Jan-Jan, I was 15 when I could go.
That's when I started listening to music more intensively.
After you finished junior high school, that's when you were born and went to college.
Jan-Jan Yes, Jan-Jan, wasn't it right around the time the Berlin Wall came down?
Higuchi, please stop talking more about history than me.
What did you listen to as a kid?
Jan-Jan, when I was a kid, Queen and...
Higuchi, wait a minute
Higuchi, don't embellish.
Yang-Yang, no, it's true.
Higuchi, really?
Queen.
Yang-Yang, Queen, it's because of my mother.
Higuchi: Your mother's pretty good.
Jan-Jan, my mother really liked Roger Taylor, the drummer of Queen.
Higuchi: Yeah, that's a big influence.
Jan-Jan Yes, that's why Queen records were always playing in the house.
So I was subconsciously listening to it all the time.
So it wasn't that I was listening to it with the intention of listening to it.
Higuchi It was playing.
Jan-Jan, the first thing I listened to was Queen.
Higuchi When I can remember, you know, it was there.
Jan-Yan, the first thing I remember from kindergarten or something was Queen.
Higuchi Queen, yes.
Higuchi: That's something.
I've been thinking about it lately.
I'm like...
I want to swim...
That's just a song.
For example
A nursery rhyme
Bloom, bloom, bloom...
Elephant, elephant, elephant...
Recently, when I see gospel music
When I see a VTR or a live video
It's as if they're singing nursery rhymes
It's gospel music that everyone sings together as if they were singing nursery rhymes
Yang Yang, well, people in America, you know
They sing in church every weekend
It's ingrained in them.
You know...
For example, you know, in our case, Tex.
The melody that pops out
I knew it would be a stylish one.
I thought they'd come out.
I guess that's what it's all about these days, isn't it?
Higuchi: Well, that's why it's called upper-class education.
Yan Yan, you say it yourself
Higuchi: I'd call it upper-class education
And I heard about Queen.
Maybe that's because I was listening to Queen.
Jan-Jan, that's huge.
And moreover, it's Queen, isn't it?
Higuchi That's right, it's a beautiful melody.
Jan-Jan, right...
So complicated!
Higuchi Yes, indeed.
The development...
That's why I'm here.
Well, this is a little...
I'm not sure if this goes along with the rest of the composition.
You know, the type of, what is it?
You know, the type of composing that's done on YouTube?
It just comes naturally.
It's just a habit of their hands and ears.It's just a habit of mine, a habit of mine.
Melodies and riffs...
You know, the melodies and riffs, they're so complicated.
That's what I mean.
Higuchi: Maybe.
I kind of like the AB Sabi, AB Sabi, AB Sabi.
I'm thinking about it.
Yang Yang, or B, then C, then D, then C, then D, then B
C and then D
Higuchi Yes, I'm tempted to go there.
Yang-Yang, after E, don't be a little confused.
Higuchi, it's F.
Higuchi: You know, you say, "Hey...
It comes out right away, or something like that.
Higuchi Maybe it's true.
Maybe...
Higuchi: It's tricky.
objectively in your mind?
Higuchi Yes, that's right.
Jan-Yan, you can make a blueprint.
I was wondering if you're a member of the Momus generation or something.
Higuchi You know...
Momus, actually, in my elementary school.
It was hopelessly out of fashion.
Yan Yan, is a generation a generation?
Higuchi: The generation is a generation of ignorance, but it is a generation.
My elementary school had 18 boys and 68 girls.
68 girls.
Jan-Jan It was like a commercial high school.
Higuchi: Yes, the opposite, like a commercial high school.
There were a lot of girls.
Jan-Jan, that's unusual.
Higuchi Why? If there were more girls, would Momus be popular?
Jan, if there were more girls, Momus would be popular.
But there's a label that girls listen to Momus.
It's like a label.
Like it's tacky for boys to listen to idol music.
Higuchi: I'm not saying I hate it, but...
Jan-yan That was the trend.
Higuchi: Wow, that's surprising.
Jan-Jan I didn't listen to Momus at all.
When I went to junior high school
When I went to junior high school, there was a guy from another elementary school.
He had a badge on his pencil case.
I thought, "Boys listen to Momus, too.
Higuchi: He said it's okay.
Yan Yan, he said it's okay.
That's why I didn't listen to them in elementary school
Higuchi, what about that kind of idol music?
What about so-called "songs"?
Jan-Jan, of course, I listened to the songs on TV shows.
I would listen to singing shows and stuff like that.
I would sing at karaoke.
Or rent CDs.
Jan-Jan, that came later.
Senior high school
Higuchi No, elementary school
That's upper grade music.
Queen and the like had been playing at home since I was five.
It was playing at home.
Jan-Yan, I'd say Queen is more important.
Higuchi: If you look at it from the roots, that's the one I listened to longer.
I listened to it for a long time.
Jan-Jan, because idols...
Like Ebituu, for example...
You're providing them, right?
You're good at making that kind of thing.
That's one of the roots of my music.
I thought I liked listening to them.
Higuchi But you're right, I didn't listen to it much.
I didn't really listen to it.
I didn't really listen to the songs you made for Ebitu.
Not so much A B chorus A B chorus
A B chorus
It's not A B chorus A B chorus.
I guess I'm more influenced by Freddie Mercury.
I think Freddie Mercury has a strong influence on me.
Yangyang That's right.
So I don't think it's intended to be listened to only by sound.
The university is not only for live performances but also for video clips.
So maybe that's also a queen thing.
Maybe it's Queen.
Except for Queen?
Around middle school.
Eminem.
And Linkin Park.
Jan-Jan... Oh, yeah, that's about it.
When I entered the seventh grade, those two were really popular.
They were all the rage.
That's where I bought CDs.
That's where I got my hip-hop leanings.
Yes, that's right.
That's how I fell in love with Linkin Park.
I learned about that rap music at Eminem.
Linkin Park raps, but their music is very alternative.
I was shocked when I entered junior high school
I was shocked when I entered junior high school.
You hadn't written any songs at that time?
Jan-Jan Yes.
When I entered junior high schoolWhen I entered junior high.
You already made it then?
There was a Nintendo DS game
There was a game for the Nintendo DS called "Ooso Band Brothers".
It's a sound game.
There was a sub-content where you could write songs.
A game.
Games. My roots are in games.
How old are you?
Fourteen.
And when did you start playing tac-rock?
That's when I was in college.
I was about 18 or 19.
I went to college and started playing in a band.
Oh, I see, so you were in a band.
I started playing in a band,
And I wanted to do something different with my band,
So I decided to make a synchronized band, and we decided to play something like an electro-rock band.
So we made a synchronized band and started playing together like an electro-rock band.
We were a band in sync.
You mean original, right?
We were doing original stuff.
At that time, in England, a genre of music called "new rave" was popular,
It was around 2006, 7 or 8.
I was influenced by that, and did electronic music.
City kids are amazing, aren't they?
No, I'm Ei Doi. I'm from there. Please don't say that.
Doinaga was born in Uji, Kyoto, a town where there is nothing but tea.
Don't worry, I've been there too.
To the purple section.
Music videos, yes.
We're shooting music videos in the same place.
That's right.
I see. But that's great. So you mean there were like-minded people who liked music?
Yes, that's right. I didn't join a university sound circle, but I joined this kind of room by myself.
I gathered a lot of people together.
At a local live music club.
I paid my own money to go out and sing live.
Oh, really?
So you want to write songs as a leader?
Yes, that's right.
I did.
And?
And the band? The band broke up. My ego got the better of me.
I always wished there were four of me, but the band members felt it.
I was so egotistical that I wished there were four of me, but the band members felt it, and they had to flee the country.
At 19? I was so sharp that I regretted it at the time.
I'm still a little obsessive about it, but...
I see. So it wouldn't work with a band. It didn't work.
But you didn't debut at that time? No debut at all. I gave up on music.
Why are you so sad about Togan?
First of all, the drummer says he's quitting, including the money.
Why would a band, still in the amateurs' stage, go so far off the deep end?
He was a bit of a stickler.
So I graduated and got a job... and decided to give up music.
But I decided I still wanted to do music, so I quit that job after 6 months.
When I was 23, I became an Okazaki carpenter.
Is this where you got your name? Okazaki Carpenter
Yes, I originally started out as Okazaki Carpenter in college.
I was posting songs on the internet.
But I didn't start performing until I was 23.
That's when I quit my job. That's when I decided to stay here.
That's right. That's when I quit my job. That's when I started teaching.
What was this? It was more like an impulse.
I had found a job once, but I thought I'd be working at the company until I was 60.
I thought it would be tough, working overtime from 9:00 a.m. to 9:00 p.m.
I thought it would be too much work... and that maybe I wasn't the right person for it.
So you went that way.
It didn't suit me.
I've been doing this for 40 years, and I feel like I'm suffocating.
I want to play music, but I can't play music because of my job?
But actually, I was 6 in favor of that and 4 in favor of quitting the company.
I still want to do music. Why didn't you say that?
What? I'm a little embarrassed. I want to do music, so I'm doing it.
You should've said so.
But I couldn't quit.
The point is... I couldn't forget the music even after work.
It's like I can't keep doing music on the side.
So I decided to do it over my dad's kids.
And then we'll get to the songwriting.
Let's go a little deeper.
First of all... you know, the Game Boy...
DS.
What do you make? Original.
At first, something like Inaho Rider.
Monpachi...
I was typing in my ear copy of Inaho Rider, Monpachi, etc.
You mean sequencers?
No, but it's pretty close to DTM.
It's kind of like DTM.
Drum Bass
Drum Bass Synthesizer
Like a garage band.
It's not that different from a garage band.
When you say it like that...
It was a bit like a game, wasn't it?
That's right.
I was playing with the music composition sub-content.
I was the only one playing with the music composition sub-content.
I was the only one who was playing with the composition sub-content, and all the junior high school students had that game.
I got a lot of praise for being able to do that, and it made me feel good.People around me praised me for being able to do that, and it made me feel really good.
The main thing is that it's not software.
The main part of the game is to press the buttons to the rhythm.
The main part of the game is to press the buttons to the rhythm, but I just happened to use the composing function in the game.
And you can play your own Inamikaze Rider songs with your friends via communication.
Wow!
So it's not a song that's built into the game.
So you can play songs that aren't included in the game.
Like, "Make this one, make this one, make this one...
I see.
I've been told...
Heh.
We did that.
And then I'm like...
It's a pleasure... to say that... that's a pleasure.
Yes.
The joy of making music.
The joy of composing.
The joy of composing music.
I see.
Yeah.
And then you made up your own original music to start a band.
That's how it all started.
In terms of how to write songs, but from that time
First of all
I often make tracks with DTM.
I start with the drums and the riffs, then add bass, chords, and the best synths.
Do you make the orchestra first?
Pre-recorded music.
That's right.
Yes, that's right.
That's what made me think you're so good at it.
I make the melody and C. Melody and C.
If the melody goes first, I can't put the C on top.
I try to put the melody with the C as much as possible.
Then the arrangement comes to my mind.
I think that's great, but I can't read music, so...
I can't read sheet music, so even if I come up with a melody first, I can't guess the chords to it.
You don't even know the chords? No, I don't.
I don't know the names.
So you can't just look at the ABC's and see how to play them?
I can't look at it and do it. You can play the keyboard, but?
I can play keys, but only chord progressions that start with an E flat.
Wow, that's great. I see.
I can't play in a session.
That's hard to play in a band... even harder. It's frustrating, isn't it?
That's right.
That's one of the reasons why I always start with a song.
Then I make the orchestra and play the chord progression by hand.
Then, I make the chord progression by hand, and make it sound good, and then add a melody that makes it even better.
Then I add the melody.
And then I write the lyrics.
And then you do the melody while you're making the lyrics.
Oh, that's right.
I'll sing the lyrics in a language that I don't know if it's English or Japanese.
I sing in a language that I don't know if it's English or not
And then I pour the Japanese verse into it.
You make it all at once?
Yes, I think so.
But if there's something I don't like, I'll fix it later, but first I make a rough draft, if not a plot.
How long does it take you to create a plot? In my head. Even from the beginning?
No, not completely. Not completely. I start by typing out the introduction on my own, and then I start to flesh it out.
So you start from the introduction. So the intro is the last part of the song? Yes, that's right.
That's great.
It's interesting.
It depends on who you ask.
Wow, that's great.
So I can't make something from the middle if I don't make it in order.
I can't make it. You didn't start from the chorus.
There might be some, but maybe one or two songs.
The intro becomes the chorus, for example.
There might be some songs like that.
You don't make choruses. No, I haven't.
Scary.
Shocking.
I didn't follow the instructions,
I make it from scratch.
For example, I can create a riff.
I can make a riff, for example, and then say something like this,
For example, a texti...
It's in me.
And there are things that sound like Queen, which you heard earlier, but there are also things that don't sound like Queen,
But there are others that are not.
That kind of inspiration, you know.
Inspiration is the presence of that "texte" that is important.
Yes, that's right.
When you make a piece, you get a sense of the textures,
And if you listen to the music, you learn your own techniques.
I often do that.
In DTM, you don't have to record it.
The pitch of the notes you type in are set to NPF.
You can change the pitch by just pulling on the keyboard.
How much of your range can you change later?
I can change the pitch of the note later.
Then, you can change the recording on the screen.
I can change it on the screen,
On the screen.
You mean you are reincarnating them?
Yes, that's right. It's not recycling.
It's what we in the Kansai region call "sub warts".
I've got subivoids.I got a suburbo.
Chicken in English.
Like chicken skin.
Oh seriously.
Yes, it is.
Interesting.
That's why it's such a rush.
I wondered why such a riff would come out.
That's how it comes out.
So, yes, it's interesting to actually have a band play it.
When you have a band play it, it's difficult to play it.
It's difficult.
It's like, "This is impossible.
This guitar is impossible.
They would say, "We took one note at a time and joined them together later.
It takes time.
Oh, really? I thought it was better not to make it look too easy.
I thought it shouldn't look too easy to make.
I know it looks easy to make. I know it's possible to make it look easy, but I thought it was a waste.
But in the end, I made a lot of changes to the song I wrote for the 24-hour live broadcast.
Oh, you did make changes, didn't you?
Oh, I don't know.
I've been having a hard time meeting deadlines lately.
It's been five or six years since I made my debut, but I used to be a very good boy who always met deadlines.
I used to be a good girl.
But in the last year or so, I've started missing deadlines by a huge margin.
What do you think about that?
I'm very sad.
Sad?
I feel sad. I don't know how it came to this.
Well, let me tell you the fundamental question. What is a deadline?
What is a deadline?
I'm talking about a concept.
If we extend this deadline by two more days, the song will be better.
That's what you're talking about, isn't it?
That's right. Of course.
But it is often said that the deadline makes the song.
I think the same way.
Is that so?
I can't write without a deadline.
I see.
The deadline is part of the work.
That's right.
But in terms of true creativity, I think too little time is not good either.
That is true.
In other words, I think you have to make your own deadlines.
Deadlines are important.
It is important to make the music up to this point, but it is also important to have the time or the sense of time,
But you have to think more about the time frame or the sense of time frame.
That is, in the long run.
I see.
There is a schedule to see if it can be done, isn't there?
That's right. So it's not so much a deadline for the song as it is a deadline for the release of the song.
That's right.
Also, when you are providing a song, you have a partner.
That requires a partner.
That's a difficult problem, isn't it?
It's a difficult problem, isn't it?
If it's your own album, you can move the release date of your own album.
you can release it on a different date.
But if you have a partner
It's a different story when you're providing the music.
Your career depends on it, doesn't it?
He's so slow to come out with songs.
You write a lot, Tyke.
There's been an increase lately.
But of course, I'm glad you're here.
I'm glad you're here. I really want to do it.
You know... on the contrary...
If I find it too difficult...
I'm sorry.
Really?
It's important for me.
Because it's me and I'm not good with words.
I can't write in a flash.
I'd like to get to know them first.
Otherwise, I can't write until I've met them once.
That's the first step.
If I can do that, then I'll do it.
It's not only about the songs I write for them, but also about my own works.
I think it's the same with my own work.
If I don't feel like I'm at the right stage of development...
I'd like to take care of that.
But I think I have to make a definite decision.
I see.
I'm not sure if I got through to you.
I don't want to go to the song.
No, no, no, no. You want to play this type of music?
Let's go to the song.
The one you struggled with?
It's a song from back in the day.
This is your last album.
It's my third album. It's from Saitama.
We couldn't make it at all.
But it was a little bit short, so I said I'd add a song.
So I made a song to be thrown away.
I call it a throwaway song.
I don't get that often.
But the ones that were written by people like Recoya and Pop...You know, the ones that you wrote for recoyers and pop-ups, like no throwaway songs.
You made a throwaway song.
That song actually got the most views on Tatsuo Okazaki's subscriber list, so I thought it would be better to make a song with a bit of elbow grease.
So I thought it would be better to make a song without being so uptight.
I'm going to play it now.
You can't do anything with Tatsuo Okazaki.
And the newest song, it just came out on the 27th of April, right?
I'm so excited about these two songs, the first one is called "Lady Cap" and the second one is called "Cap Revolution Bottle Man".
This is called Cap Revolution Bottleman DX.
It's a plastic bottle cap.
You blow the caps off and hit the target.
It's a toy that you blow the caps off and hit the target.
It's called Bottleman.
There used to be a toy called B-Daman.
I used to fly Biderman.
In the age of SDGs
Bottle caps
caps to fly away.
A toy cartoon started recently
started the other day.
The theme song
It's called "Lady Cap".
When the caps fly off the bottle...
It's called "Lady Cap.
Jan-Yan, the word used in the cartoon.
Higuchi Yes, that's right.
I wrote a song for it.
Yan Yan, lyricist and composer
Higuchi Writing lyrics and arranging music
Jan-Jan You've written some songs for anime too
Higuchi Animation, yes, like Pocket Monsters.
Yang Yang Of course, they would first ask you to do something like this.
Higuchi Yes, they wanted a song that was a little more energetic, something that children could dance to.
Something that children can dance to.
Higuchi: They're here.
Higuchi: And this time?
Yang Yang This time it's an energetic piece.
Of course, it's an energetic piece.
You just said that.
You mentioned the SDGs.
Higuchi: You're including that too?
Yang Yang: Yes, from Mr. Takaratomi's side.
It's a toy that takes the SDGs into account.
So it's like we've found a treasure in the junk.
It's like we found a treasure in the junk.
The lyrics are in the chorus.
in the chorus.
Also, the main character's voice...
The main character's voice, or a key line from the anime.
So we were asked to include it in the song.
or something like that.
That's something you don't do on your own albums.
It's not something you can do on your own album.
How to respond to people's requests is what I do.
I think that's what's interesting about this kind of music
I think that's what's interesting about tie-ups.
Higuchi: I'm the type of person who gets a little excited when an order comes in.
If I get an order...
Yangyang Yes, I'm more excited when I get orders.
Higuchi I see.
Yan Yan, respect
Higuchi Yuki-chan seems to be good at it too
Yang Yang, I get tied up a lot
I have Japanese paper to begin with
Plus, I get orders like that.
I can't think about SDGs
Edo can only talk about SDGs
The Edo period was originally...
It's like the Edo period was a time of "eko".
Higuchi: That's right.
It's exciting, isn't it?
When it fits perfectly...
Yang Yang When it fits, the client's response is...
Higuchi I love it!
Jan-Yan, that's amazing!
Higuchi: It's a great feeling to hear that.
You have a craftsman's spirit, too.
I've always wanted to do that.
Ever since I was a child.
I wrote in my elementary school graduation album that I wanted to be a composer.
I see.
I didn't really think about singing in the public eye as a child.
I didn't really think about singing in front of the stage as a child.
You were a bit of a backstage kind of guy, weren't you?
That's right.
I didn't want to sing my own songs.
I wanted the world to listen to my songs, even if I didn't sing them myself.
Yes, it was a pleasure to compose songs together with everyone else.
Yes, that's right.
And the song "Season's Tidings.
This is the theme song for an evening TV show in Kansai called "News Okaeri".
It's the theme song for a Kansai evening TV program called News Okaeri.
It's a little different from the previous song, Lady Captor, because it's for the main target audience, the evening housewives.
It's a song that makes people feel warm and fuzzy inside.
The image I had in mind was to make a song that was clearly SUMIKA-esque.
I see... this is "SUMIKA"... this is "SUMIKA" with a little SUMIKA motif...
I added some elements of Tetsu Okazaki. What's the relationship between this and SUMIKA? Not really.
I don't have much of a relationship with SUMIKA... but I know his personality and he greeted me in a very humble way, so...
I like him a lot, but I want to write a song like Sumika.
This song was arranged not by me, but by Yoichiro Nomura, and he made it sound like Sumika.
I'm not going to say it like that, but it's better to say it clearly so that the audience can understand it.I'm not saying that, but it's better to say it clearly so that the message is conveyed.
It's not like I'm trying to make it my own, but I'm saying, "This song already has a reference.
It's more comfortable for me to say, "I reverted to Smika.
I do that a lot with engineers and such.
Even if I say it in a roundabout way, it's still conveyed as a song in the end.
There are times when I tell them, "This is it, this is the song.
Sometimes I send the libretto as it is.
It's like you're sharing the best parts with them.
That's right.
In other words, we ask everyone to share their own songs as well.
No matter how many references we use, we can't make exactly the same thing.
I think it's important to share references with everyone on the team.
I've been emphasizing the importance of sharing references with my team recently.
And when it's completed, there's a sense of accomplishment.
It's very effective, isn't it?
It's a good thing, isn't it?
Next, let's talk about the live performance.
Well, this is a bit like today's radio show.
It's a long story, isn't it?
We are.
We talk a lot.
I wonder why.
The MC is long, isn't he?
To be honest, our history is longer.
When we played at the Budokan, how many hours did we play that day?
About an hour and a half.
An hour and a half? I bet it was longer than that.
Three hours. I remember we had to pay for an extension.
Really?
If you don't pay the extra time at the Budokan, they say they'll extend it.
How many songs did you play in those three hours?
We must have played a lot.
Ten?
12 or 3 songs.
That's right.
Usually in about three hours.
12 or 3 songs in 3 hours... a lot... a lot.
But still... actually... the ending roll...
Yes, yes, yes.
I cut it.
I was told I had to experience it again.
So I cried and cried.
I don't know what to do
I made it, but I'm cutting it.
MC's been here longer than you
I wonder...
Why are you talking like this?
Me? I'm taking a break.
Is there a reason you're writing?
Yes, I do.
You're kidding.
No, I'm telling you the truth.
I'm just talking and waiting for you to catch your breath.
Really?
It's true.
You don't look like that.
Is he breathing?
I'm breathing.
Are you sure?
It's so congested.
One more song and you'll be fine.
Well, it's moving like crazy.
All over the place.
It's moving like crazy.
Is it amazing?
That's why my blood vessels are in trouble.
You drink a lot of water.
I drink a lot of water.
Is that right?
Yes.
Clearly, a break.
I'm the opposite.
I don't even have time to drink water.
I'll talk.
Why is that?
I mean...
You want to talk?
I talk a lot.
I'm not trying to talk.
I'm told every time by the staff not to talk.
Don't talk.
I'm told every time to go compact.
I'm told every time.
I'm still getting told off for today.
And when I go to someone's concert
And if I talk too long...
I think it's too long.
That sucks.
Even though I'm long.
You think it's long.
I don't get it.
I don't know why.
I want you to tell me.
Why is that?
But... you know, I'm not a vocalist.
I'm not a vocalist.
It's the same with your collaborations.
I'm anxious that I can't show you what I can do.
I'm anxious about not being able to show it.Anxiety.
Then I feel like I have to cover the production side.
I felt like I had to cover up for him in terms of direction.
So I had to cover that feeling by talking.
MC?
The production and the MC are two different things.
It's because of your influence.
I was influenced by you, too.
But the production side...
It's fun to do elaborate productions.
So you like comedy, too?
You like comedy a lot?
Yes, I do.
I'm from Kansai.
Comedy shows have always been a part of my life.
I think that's one of the influences.
Were you ever interested in being a comedian or anything like that?
I never wanted to be a comedian.
But I like going to comedy shows.
I like comedy a lot.
You are trying to incorporate those elements into your live performances.
Yes, that's right.
I think I use some of that as a reference.
So of course you compose music.
I'm always told that.
It's easy for people to see us as a storyteller.
I might be going back to the composition.
We don't mean it that way.
We're making music.
It just happens to be the theme of the piece.
just because that's the theme.
We're actually just making music seriously
We're just making music seriously.
But at a live show, we put those elements in.
We want to entertain people
That's the way it's going to be.
But you don't dislike it, right?
I don't dislike it.
How do you balance it all?
Balance.
But you also have to be careful not to go too far, don't you?
Yes, that's right.
Video clips
Before our debut, we performed at a live house in Nara.
At a live house in Nara before our debut.
We did a live show with a band.
We also did a comical one once.
With Heter
And a comical one with Hetter.
With Heter.
Once with Hetter
And we sold a lot of tickets that day.
And when we were doing a show with serious songs
I was slipping really hard.
The audience didn't want that.
Not at all.
They said, "Well, it's a good song.
But there was no passion at all as a live performance.
I realized that it wasn't the same.
I realized that Okazaki Tatsuki should do what Okazaki Tatsuki is supposed to do.
I thought it was a good idea to do what Okazaki Tatsuki does.
That was the day I realized that.
What made you decide to play a serious song?
I mean, it made me feel alive.
If you play only serious songs...
That's what I like about it.
I like that it's alive.
I really like that you always say that.
It makes me want to live.
We only played serious songs.
We didn't have a lot of MCs that day.
I didn't want to show that this wasn't all.
I didn't want to show it.
I wanted to expand my own furoshiki.
I wanted to expand my own froshki, but it was hard to get a good feeling with the audience.
Yes, it was.
To put it another way...
The customers know you're serious, right?
That's right.
Even if they do comical things...
Even if they're doing comical things, they know you understand them.
Without realizing it, they still do it.
The question I wanted to ask Ike-chan...
Why do you do live concerts?
That's right.
When I was asked this question, I had an epiphany when I saw this.
You're right.
It's not because there's a mountain of them, for example.
It's because we've always thought that we should do live concerts.
Everyone.
After they release their CDs, they go on live tours and stuff.
It's just something we take for granted.
I never really thought about it.
I've never thought about it, but it's true that I wonder why we do live shows.
I guess.
I thought that too.
I wanted to listen to it.
But maybe they're not really linked.
CDs, sound files, and live performances...
You can't talk about them, can you?
But on the contrary, they are completely different things.But on the contrary, they're completely different.
That's right.
Hey, hey, hey.
What?
You know it.
You know it!
Answer.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
I have my own answer.
I see.
Is that what you're asking me?
Yes, I do.
Well, I'll tell you something else.
No, no, no, no, no.
Can I say something?
Go ahead.
I'm self-prominent.
Well, you could write a song about it.
I could write a song about it.
With the naked eye.
I see.
I want to feel it in real life.
I want people to experience what I'm doing with my music, and I want it to be a part of their once-in-a-lifetime life.
I want people to feel that my music will be a part of their once-in-a-lifetime life, even if only for a moment.
I hope that the music of Okazaki Carpenter
will be a part of your life
I think it's cool
I think it feels good.
I'm influencing them.
I'm influencing each and every one of their lives.
I'm affecting each and every one of their lives.
Even if it's just one line.
That's what I want to live for.
Higuchi, me too.
Yang Yang, stop it!
I don't know...
Fukai I was thinking the exact same thing Higuchi, I just stole it.
Fukai Don't tell me you stole it.
Higuchi, come on
Yang-Yang, you stole it!
My cool guy...
We're not werewolves.
Yang-Yang, 10 people were killed by this.
Higuchi, looks like an old tire
Jan-Jan, I'm calling you Mako now.
Fukai I see what you mean, but...
But I've got that too.
Jan-Jan, have you?
Fukai That's right, that's right.
That's why I often say
I often say, "There are 100 people, but there are 10,000 people.
It's not 10,000 people.
I'm doing it for each and every one of them, right?
So, to put it another way, even if it's just one person...
In the sense that you're giving the same live performance even to just one person.
That may be true.
To a personal person.
But there's also the desire for self-dedication.
Jan-Yan Yes, I do.
Fukai But on the other hand...
But on the other hand, I don't want to be too self-congratulatory
I don't want to overstate how great I am.
Jan-Jan, I can't help it.
It makes me feel good.
Doing it.
It's like I'm the whole world now.
I feel like I'm the whole world now.
It's...
It's entertainment.
I don't know, I don't know.
I don't think we can look at it objectively and calmly
Only in our own world
It's like it's all good.
It's like it's all good in our world.
Yang-Yang, you mean "in our house"?
Jan-Jan, that's why I'm trying to be careful.
That's why we have to be careful about that.
That's why.
Of course it's fine to like yourself.
But you have to look at it objectively at some point.
I don't mean to go that far.
Higuchi: Let me ask you again.
Why do you do live concerts?
Jan-Yan, I guess it's because there are people there who want to listen to you.
Because there are people who want to hear it. Live.
Higuchi: Oh, because there's a mountain there.
Jan-Jan, I was joking at first.
But that's pretty much it, isn't it?
Even if it's just one person, they'll still want to do it, right?
Higuchi: There are people who want to see the history live.
There are people who want to see us perform.
They actually buy tickets and come to the venue.
And they come to the venue by train or whatever.
And if they say "yan yan," then we'll do it for them.
Higuchi: Isn't that the final point?
Yang-Yang, that's really cool!
Higuchi Was it cooler this way?
Yang Yang, I don't like it.
That's what I was thinking too.That's what I'm doing too.
Higuchi Smokey
Yang Yang Smoke together
Higuchi We smother each other
Jan, but you're right... it's important to make sure
It's important to make sure we're on the same page
Higuchi That's right, isn't it?
Jan-Jan, we don't have many launches these days.
We're in this kind of situation.
We don't talk about deep things like this without alcohol.
Higuchi That's why we have to talk about these things on a regular basis.
That's true, we have to make sure.
Higuchi That's right.
I'll see you here.
I thought Tyke was the most amazing artist I've ever seen live.
I've seen live.
Higuchi Yes, at Summer Sonic.
I went with a friend when I was a freshman in college.
Jan-Yan, how long ago was that?
Higuchi Well, let's see...
About 12 years ago.
We saw the Flaming Lips.
Higuchi: It was a great place.
Higuchi: It was incredible.
It was just a bunch of old guys joking around.
They looked like they were having so much fun.
There were so many people on stage.
There were a little more people than in the past.
The people on stage
They were so jovial.
I still have an impression of how they were having so much fun
I still have a strong impression of that.
I'd like to play a song I heard at that time.
Race for the Prize by the Flaming Lips.
I don't want to break up with you
I don't want to break up with you.
Let's do it again... on the regular.
I'm serious.
For Tyke, it's all kinds of things... songwriting, live performances, all kinds of music.
It's not just music that motivates him. What motivates him to do interesting things?
What do you think? It's the driving force behind my music.
And this is for the makers. To build a house.
I see.
A big house.
No, that's it.
I think it's great. Really?
Ken Takakura once asked me what an actor means to him.
He said, "To make money.
That's right.
I said it's work.
I have a dream to make money and build a big house.
If that becomes my driving force, I can entertain tens of thousands of people.
I'm going to write good songs.
That's important.
There's something that's not just a pretty face.
And that's typical of Tyke.
That's right.
Even if I say so...
I'm proud of the fact that I have an image that's not dirty.
And I think that if a character like me says things like that, it will probably make it easier for the latercomers to say them.
I think it will make it easier for the younger generation to say what they want to say.
That's good to hear about the driving force.
By the way, Ike-chan...
By the way, Ikechan? Yes.
Looking for a motive force?
Are you looking for it? Are you looking for it?
You look so cool on the way over.
That's not fair.
That's the easiest and the cheesiest.
I don't know what to say. Just say you're looking for it.
I'll say I'm looking for you.
I'll say I'm looking for it.
I'll say I'm still trying to figure out which I like better.
That's right. I'm still thinking about which I like better.
That's a good lesson for me from a senior.
Well, that was fun. Thank you very much. Thank you, really. Let's go out for dinner, really. Really.
So there's going to be a second episode? If there is, if it's in the script. I'd love to have it. Thank you very much. Excuse me.
I've been navigating through the history of Ikeda, WOW MUSIC, how was it?
Our next guest is guitarist and vocalist Atsushi Osawa from Uchikyokumon Doyukai.
I'm sure it's going to be an in-depth discussion, so please listen to the show and we'll see you next week.